[Melody of Golden Age]
[Episode 1]
[Cang State Palace]
Salute.
In the fifth year of the Yuanhe Era of Cang State,
Emperor Wenzong Xiao Huan
and the former Crown Prince died of disease successively.
[Zhou Xu, Empress Dowager of Cang State]
Xiao Qi, grandson of the former emperor,
who was still an infant, ascended the throne.
The era name was changed into Shengli.
The queen Zhou Xu, who had long been assisting in government affairs,
was honored as the grand empress dowager.
She attended to state affairs
and became the most powerful person in the state.
Long live the Emperor, long live the Emperor!
[Six years later]
[Training Ground, Imperial Security Bureau]
Grand Commander.
We were interrogating the suspects all night.
All of them have confessed to their crimes.
But they refused to reveal the mastermind behind it.
White...
White Ghost!
[Shen Du, Grand Commander of the Imperial Security Bureau]
I...
I'll confess.
I only helped them transport the people.
There was a buyer in Jiannan
who wanted a hundred children to be slaves.
Take them away.
Next time,
don't wait for me to do this myself.
Yes.
Let's go to the palace.
Mother, I heard that you were saddened
by the death of the state preceptor
and that you were not feeling well.
So I copied scriptures until dawn,
[Xiao Zhong, Prince Xian]
praying for your recovery.
It's so kind of you to do so.
I really appreciate it.
[Xiao Qi, the young emperor]
Minister Zhang, you're being a wonderful teacher
to him.
[Zhang Xingwei, prime minister]
I'm flattered.
His Highness, Prince Xian,
is a man of loyalty and filial piety
and has a kind heart.
[Princess Ying, Princess Yong'an]
He's born with a good nature.
How come Lord Shen didn't come to court today?
Grand Commander Shen is busy with his work
[Lai Luozhi, Minister of Imperial Investigation Department]
and has repeatedly achieved remarkable feats.
Perhaps
[Xu Wan, Internal Officer]
he has no time to attend court.
Shen Du, Grand Commander of the Imperial Security Bureau, has arrived.
Greetings, Your Royal Highness.
Please rise, Lord Shen.
Your Royal Highness.
Just now, I was
investigating the case
of a hundred children who were missing.
All suspects have confessed.
I apologize for being late,
and beg for your forgiveness,
This case caused
a lot of fear in the Xiang'an City.
I really made a right decision
to let you handle the case.
Lord Shen.
As it happens,
early this morning, Minister Zhang
requested a reward
from me for you.
Grand Commander Shen
always manages to turn the tide.
He is truly a model for all of us.
Thank you for your compliment, Minister Zhang.
It is the duty of the Imperial Security Bureau.
I require no reward.
Minister Zhang and the Imperial Security Bureau
have always been at odds.
Have you
buried the hatchet recently?
Yong'an.
I'm sorry.
Seeing my officials are all on good terms,
I feel I'm lucky to have you.
Lord Shen.
Today,
let me choose a wife for you.
What do you think?
White Ghost has always been at will.
Master, how did you know
[East Side Hall]
that he would agree to marry
the girl chosen by the grand empress dowager?
Shen Du is known as White Ghost
To others, he's a brutal man who has killed lots of people.
But to the grand empress dowager,
he is no more than an official who hopes to
rise through the ranks and win Her Highness's favor.
Is he afraid that if he says no
to the marriage arrangement,
he will lose the trust from the grand empress dowager?
Even if you're a ghost,
you would have human desires.
Xing.
-Xing.
-Morning, Xing.
Morning.
-Xing.
-Morning.
-Morning, Xing.
-Xing.
Morning.
Miss Yan, you're so early.
Be careful.
I just dried these flower petals.
[Yan Xing, a scribe in the Ministry of Justice]
I'm sorry, Miss Yan.
It's alright.
-Morning, Yan Xing.
-Morning.
-Morning, Xing.
[Ministry of Justice]
Didn't you
have breakfast this morning?
How come you're so clumsy?
You see?
What can a woman do
in the Ministry of Justice?
If what you said is heard
by Officer Xu who's often with the grand empress dowager,
you will be blamed for disrupting her plan
to get women to work for the government.
Why do you have so much to say today?
You have nothing to do, huh?
Get to work.
File them.
My Lord.
[Wu Taiming, a section chief of the Ministry of Justice]
Yan Xing.
Get the tea.
My Lord.
Today,
the constables
gave us a case
from Mount Yangui.
It's said a woman from a household
met a ghost
and hung herself.
My Lord, let me tell you.
My subordinates and I
have an awful lot of trivial cases
to deal with like this one.
My bros and I
don't even
have time to eat,
let alone sleep.
I've made a request for more manpower
from higher-ups.
Right.
Two years ago,
we finally got to recruit a clerk.
But...
It's a woman.
Take this.
When the constables
finish their investigation and report back,
just file it.
Don't complicate it.
Yes.
[My mother was hanging herself from a beam and when we got her down, she was not breathing.]
[His husband Cheng suspected testimony and got up early to see his wife in the hall]
Mount Yangui.
Suicide.
You people in the Xiang'an City pay little respect to the dead.
In my hometown,
we wouldn't dare to hang colorful ribbons after a county magistrate died.
It's only been a month
since the state preceptor died.
But there are lanterns and decorations everywhere in the city.
People here seem not to care about his death.
You know nothing.
The state preceptor was
a great sage who knew the will of heaven.
He
even prophesied the current
grand empress dowager's reign.
Really?
The place where he died was said to be a magical place.
Today, all officials are going to pay their respects there.
Black Rakshasa is coming! Black Rakshasa is coming!
Quick, run!
Hide quickly!
Who is it?
Why is everyone
acting like they've seen a ghost?
You didn't hear about Black Rakshasa?
He established the Imperial Investigation Department.
It specializes in espionage and inquisition by torture.
It's said there are over a hundred
torture devices in there.
Once one is brought in,
they will confess.
If they refuse to confess,
they'll be extremely painful.
White Ghost is here!
White Ghost is also here!
So that isWhite Ghost.
White Ghost
is Grand Commander Shen of the Imperial Security Bureau.
Imperial Security Bureau is quite something.
It is directly managed by the grand empress dowager.
Investigation, surveillance, assassination;
they do them all.
Stop crying.
White Ghost of the Underworld is here.
Wherever he goes,
clouds scatter in broad daylight
and children dare not cry.
The two lord's convoys
are going to encounter.
We'll have a great show to watch.
The street is only this wide.
Who do you think will make way?
Who knows?
Let's see.
Stop.
Grand Commander Shen, you're here after all.
I thought
you'd be too busy preparing for your wedding
and couldn't make it.
My wedding
is nothing compared to matters of the state.
Minister Zhang advised the marriage.
The grand empress dowager agreed.
It shows your marriage affair
is also a matter of great importance.
It's a pity
that your previous fiancées
were not so fortunate.
Lord Lai, you're joking.
The auspicious time is coming soon.
Let's hurry if we don't want to miss it.
This West Street is too narrow.
It can't even accommodate
two convoys.
Clear out everything blocking the way
on both sides
so the Investigation convoy and the Security convoy
can go along at the same time.
Grand Commander.
Let's go.
Shen Du.
You've really kept me waiting.
Minister Zhang.
I'm sorry for being late.
You're not late.
In fact, you arrived at the perfect time.
Everyone.
Let's begin the ceremony.
The auspicious time has come.
Thank you, Miss Yan.
If you hadn't come,
[Jiang Langxing, a constable]
we wouldn't have been able to identify the real culprit.
You're welcome.
Investing
is part of the Ministry of Justice's responsibilities.
By the way,
a few days ago,
you asked us to help find
herbs that can detect poison.
I've found where they are.
There are some on the mountain nearby.
How about you get in our carriage and go with us
to the mountain and pick some?
Don't bother.
You should hurry back and report.
I'll go up the mountain to pick them myself.
Then
I'll take my leave.
Till next time.
Today's blessing ceremony
was successful thanks to
Minister Zhang's organization.
Next year, our Cang State
will enjoy peace
and prosperity
as the state preceptor predicted.
Today, all officials came to pray for blessings.
That's because Prince Xian
visited a saint among the commoners
and chose today as the auspicious time
to solve problems for the grand empress dowager.
I was merely following orders
and fulfilling my duty as Her Royal Highness's official.
Our Cang State
has wise rulers and good officials.
We subjects are fortunate to live
in this prosperous era of peace and stability.
We're so lucky.
Indeed.
Assassin!
Seal off the mountain!
Miss.
Are you gathering these leaves to make medicine?
No.
I want to use them for autopsy...
Yes.
I want to use them to make medicine.
How did you know?
I could tell from the way you are dressed.
[Qi Yeyun]
You're a physician, right?
You can say so.
Here, take these.
I've gathered enough.
Ms. Zhang at the village entrance is ill.
I came to pick some for her.
The other day, the doctor said
drinking it as tea would be helpful.
Then let me pay you.
Please don't.
I just picked them casually.
Well, thank you then.
Miss.
My name is Qi Yeyun.
What's your name?
Are you heading down the mountain, Miss?
Let me show you a shortcut.
It'll be quicker.
Stop! Stop!
Today,
no one can leave the mountain.
What happened?
I'm a scribe from the Ministry of Justice
No more talk.
Go with us.
-Go!
What's going on here?
Lord Lai.
At the time of the incident,
only these people were ion the mountain and they're all here.
On the day of the blessing ceremony at the Ming Hall,
someone
dared to attempt an assassination on a court official.
I luckily dodged the arrow.
But I lost one of my beloved subordinates.
Today,
I must kill the assassin!
Assassin?
Who is the assassin?
One of you is the assassin.
I advise the assassin
to confess now.
Then
I won't let you die in pain.
If you dare not confess,
you will still be found guilty.
In 30 minutes,
if no one confesses,
all of you will be killed.
Wait.
Lord Lai.
I am Yan Xing, a scribe from the Ministry of Justice.
May I examine the dead body?
Maybe I can find out
who the assassin is.
Okay.
It's between 5 to 7 p.m. now.
The sun is in the west.
So the place where they shot...
Well, little scribe.
Can you tell me
who the assassin is now?
I haven't yet determined
who the assassin is.
However,
the assassin shot from a long distance.
The sun is shining brightly today
and it will make it difficult for them to aim.
So he must have been in
a shaded area at the time of the assassination.
Considering the direction
of the arrow,
the best hiding spot
is in a tree.
The assassin must have been in the woods
high on the mountain in the northwest.
After the incident,
the Imperial Investigation Department immediately sealed off the mountain.
Therefore, the people in other mountain ranges
couldn't possibly be the assassin.
Lord Lai.
I implore you
to release the innocent civilians
first.
I have already made myself
very clear.
If you want me to release them,
you have to find out who the assassin is first.
You failed to do that.
I'll just kill them all.
Lord Lai.
I have a more interesting idea.
Shooting the assassin to death
is not intimidating enough.
I have kept several fighting dogs.
Their ability to tear criminals apart
is quite amazing.
Why don't we let my dogs
bite them?
Although it might take more time,
it's
more entertaining, right?
People call me Black Rakshasa.
But it seems
you're even more brutal than me.
You won.
Your idea is better.
Jing Lin.
Stop!
Let them stop.
Go away!
Go away! Go away!
One of them is the assassin.
The assassin must be
someone with great strength and speed,
and skilled at climbing.
Lord Lai.
You should
do something about them.
Let me think
what way of killing them
would suit them better.
Lord Lai, I implore you
to wait a while more.
Just give me a little more time,
and I'll find
the one and only assassin.
I stake my life on it.
Grand Commander Shen.
How much time
do you think I should give her?
Six hours.
Six hours later,
if you can't find who the real assassin is,
you'll die with them.
[Imperial Security Bureau]
Those who use bows and arrows
develop calluses in three places on their hands.
This person only has calluses on his palm.
Ruled out.
[Grand Commander's Office]
Grand Commander.
Lai Luozhi is the one who wants to find the assassin.
But he sent the suspects here
and let us handle the case.
He said
he wanted us to use the fighting dogs to punish them.
Do you think
there is a trap for us?
What kind of trap could there be?
He's just certain
that little scribe can't find the real assassin.
He doesn't want to kill anyone from the Ministry of Justice either
because he wants to avoid getting his hands dirty.
If he doesn't want to get his hands dirty,
aren't you afraid
there will be gossip about you?
I've already been the son of a guilty minister.
I'm not afraid of any rumors.
The assassin's location
is at the peak of the northwest mountain.
And that planted forest
is a lacquer tree forest.
Someone touched the branches of a lacquer tree,
and broke out in rashes all over their body.
When the guards
caught the suspects during the day,
none of them had any rashes on their bodies.
Those with severe rashes
can be ruled out
as possibly hiding in the lacquer tree forest.
There is this person in the middle.
The mud on his shoes
is not from the lacquer tree forest.
Ruled out.
Once we find the weapon the assassin used,
we'll know who the killer is.
Why is it so bright?
Do you have any last words?
Six hours are almost up.
You still haven't found out who the assassin is.
When the Imperial Guards
found the weapon used by the assassin in the lacquer tree forest,
and we take a closer look at it,
-then...
-No need to explain.
You have no any more time to wait.
Even if you find the weapon,
you're not completely certain, are you?
Am I right?
Just because we're not completely certain,
we shouldn't do it?
You're not completely certain,
but you staked your life.
So you're either extremely foolish
or have no self-respect.
I'll leave a letter then.
Please deliver it
to Dr. Yan's residence in the east of the city.
Take Miss Yan away.
Get her to be properly killed.
Yes, sir.
Grand Commander Shen.
Do you really not know me?
Should I?
Grand Commander.
The assassin's weapon has been found,
Just as Miss Yan guessed,
it was buried under the fallen leaves in the lacquer tree forest.
It seems Miss Yan is lucky this time.
The weapon
was found in the last minute.
By comparing the bow and arrow
with the calluses on the suspect's hands,
I can determine who the assassin is.
It seems I have good luck today.
I've come at just the right time.
Lord Lai, you came at the perfect timing.
I'm afraid it's not just because of luck.
The weapon was transported
from Mount Yangui to the Imperial Security Bureau.
The news must have
reached the Imperial Investigation Department long ago.
The six hours are up.
Miss Yan, hurry up.
I'm very curious to see
who was so bold
to try to kill me.
Gentlemen.
Please
use the bow and arrow
as you normally would.
I think I know who the assassin is.
The calluses on both suspects from using the bow
are almost the same.
However, their calluses from preparing the arrow
are different.
One
has the calluses on the inside of his thumb,
indicating that he uses
the inside of his thumb to support the arrow.
This bow-holding technique
is known by skilled archers.
It is the slanted low-push method.
It lacks accuracy in archery.
The other one
has calluses on the place where the root of his thumb joins the root of the index finger,
which is the correct high-push method.
It's good for precise shooting.
Therefore,
the assassin is you.
Don't move! Don't move.
Step back! Step back!
Don't come near me!
Let me go!
Or I'll kill her!
Don't you realize where you are?
You think you can escape?
Tell me who's behind this.
And I might keep your dead body whole.
Release her now!
Since we've got all the evidences,
we don't need your confession.
Prepare to shoot.
You...
Are you going to shoot her too?
She's not one of the Imperial Security Bureau.
She's a petty scribe
without any rank.
I'll lose nothing
if she dies.
Shen Du.
You heartless White Ghost.
How can you act as if human life is not worth a straw?
If you died with the suspect,
I'll consider you as a patriot.
As far as I know,
the salary of a scribe is very little.
The Ministry of Justice has always been
the one that gives the highest compensation among the six ministries.
Your parents will gain benefits from raising you.
Even if I become a ghost,
I won't let you off.
What a coincidence,
I'm not afraid
of ghosts at all.
Don't move! Don't move!
Thank you.
You're not stupid.
Since there's no way out,
alright then.
Tell me!
Who sent you to kill me?
It's...
It's him.
Grand Commander Shen.
No wonder you were in such a hurry to kill him.
Awesome.
Lord Lai.
How can you believe the nonsense
of the assassin before he died?
That's ridiculous.
Who do you think you are?
How dare you speak to my lord like this!
Lord Lai, please think carefully.
If it's the grand commander who sent the killer,
why would the Imperial Security Bureau
bother to arrest so many people
and search for the assassin's weapon?
Wouldn't it have been better to kill them from the start?
I was just joking.
How could I believe you wanted to kill me?
Don't take it seriously.
I
never took it seriously.
Now that the culprit has been brought to justice,
I can rest easy.
It's not good for me to stay at the Imperial Security Bureau any longer.
I'll take my leave.
I failed in my duty to watch the suspect.
Please punish me, Grand Commander.
Let it go since he is dead.
You guys,
take Miss Yan
and others
out of here.
Yes.
Grand Commander.
I noticed that the young female scribe
was staring at you the whole time.
She's not afraid of you at all.
What's so surprising about that?
In the Xiang'an City,
there're always so many boring women.
Indeed.
Your appearance
can indeed attract some
brainless women who like handsome guys.
If you dare to talk nonsense again,
I'll send you to work at the Imperial Investigation Department.
Please don't!
I just want to work for the Imperial Security Bureau
for the rest of his life.
I got it.
The lady Yan Caiwei you're going to marry
is from Dr. Yan's family.
Yan Xing
is your fiancée's sister.
She
is clever.
She knew what I was doing
was to save her.
But whether she'll be my sister-in-law
depends on whether her third sister
has the courage
to marry me, Shen Du, as my wife.
This...
Thank you, Miss Yan, for risking your life to save us.
Please rise.
I work at the Ministry of Justice.
It was my duty.
But for your excellent case-solving skills,
we wouldn't be able
to make it back to see our families.
It's late at night.
Go back home now.
Thank you again, Miss Yan.
Let's go.
Miss.
Today I see how you solved a case.
You are so clever
and you didn't escape in the face of danger.
You saved my life.
Come up.
So I want you to be my teacher.
Please don't say no, Miss.
I'm still just
a scribe without a rank.
How can I be your teacher?
Besides,
your parents
won't allow
you to take a woman as your teacher.
I have no parents.
I was brought up
by the villagers in Yangui Mountain Village.
I want you to be my teacher.
Please accept me.
[Lu Chuichui, a secretariat of Ministry of Justice]
But she may not
want you to be his disciple.
Boy.
Miss.
Is that so?
Get in the carriage, Xing.
Let's go.
By the way.
How did you know
I was at the Imperial Security Bureau?
I got the news
from the clerk
in the shop near my house.
He said
his cousin's classmate's
cousin's sister-in-law
saw in Yangui Mountain Village
that some villagers
and a female scribe from the Ministry of Justice
were taken to the Imperial Security Bureau.
So it was a female scribe
from the Ministry of Justice.
Who else could it be but you?
Well, it seems
that shop clerk
is more suited for the Ministry of Justice than you are.
At first, when I heard about it,
I was so worried.
But then I knew
you were there to investigate a case.
Then
I was not worried at all.
There's not any case
that you, Yan Xing,
can't solve.
Besides,
you know someone
from the Imperial Security Bureau.
Don't tell me
Shen Du
hasn't recognized you yet.
Is he blind or something?
Anyway, forget about that.
I think I'd better take you home first.
I'm not going home.
Just drop me off at the Ministry of Justice.
The Ministry of Justice?
Yan Xing.
Tomorrow is the registration date for the female official examination?
The women in the Xiang'an City
all want to be like your third sister
who is a famous,
talented, elegant,
noble lady.
Only you are so determined
to become a female official.
You're already a female official.
I can't fall too far behind, can I?
Don't worry.
This year, I'll definitely become
a real female official of the Ministry of Justice.
Turn right ahead.
Go to the Ministry of Justice.
My Lord.
The assassin we sent has committed suicide on the spot.
Then
the battle between them two
will become more interesting.
The state preceptor made a final prophecy
before his death.
Have you found out what it was about?
It is said that
besides "The phoenix leads nine holy birds,"
and "peace reigns under heaven,"
there's another half to the prophecy.
But no one said what it was.
It seems no one knows.
On the night the state preceptor died,
White Ghost and Black Rakshasa
were both in the Ming Hall.
These two
are really unpredictable.
[Yan's Mansion]
What happened?
I am the sixth daughter of the Yan family.
Let me in.
In accordance with heaven's will and the times,
I have received this clear mandate.
The Yan family has a daughter
with a talent for poetry.
[Yan's Mansion]
She's good with words
and excellent at embroidery.
She is well-versed in classics and virtuous in conduct,
knowledgeable in both ancient and modern affairs.
Her reputation as a virtuous and talented lady
-is well known in the Xiang'an City.
-Mother.
I am greatly pleased to hear of this.
Now, Shen Du, Grand Commander of the Imperial Security Bureau
is of marriageable age.
[Yan's Mansion]
A worthy fiancée should be chosen for him.
As the Yan family's daughter is of marriageable age,
she and Shen Du are a match made in heaven.
In doing a good deed,
I hereby
[Yan's Mansion]
request you to be man and wife in three days.
The end.
Dr. Yan.
Please take the imperial edict.
Shen Du?
I thank grand empress dowager for her goodwill.
[Yan Kuo, master of the Yan family]
Thank you.
Congratulations, Dr. Yan,
on educating Lady Caiwei so well
[Yan Caiwei, third daughter of the Yan family]
that she's become a virtuous noble lady famous in Xiang'an.
Oh, my Caiwei.
Caiwei cannot marry!
A girl's marriage
has always been decided by her parents
and arranged by matchmakers.
Moreover,
this decision is made by the grand empress dowager.
But he's White Ghost.
If our Caiwei marries him,
she...
She'll be miserable.
[Ms. Jin, Yan Kuo's concubine]
Life is so unpredictable.
This is beyond anyone's expectation.
It's so tragic.
Mother.
Why are staring at me?
People say
truly wise people look foolish.
Are you one of those people?
I always feel that I
have no ability and no status.
I gave birth to you and you're only a concubine's daughter.
and because of that, you're unwelcome.
That's why I've always wanted you to
learn from your third sister
to behave like a lady
so you marry into a good family in the future
and have a better life for the rest of your life.
Mother.
You know I don't like those things.
Yes.
I used to get angry too,
always blaming you for being stupid,
uneducated and incompetent.
But now,
I suddenly feel
being uneducated and incompetent is not bad.
Being uneducated and incompetent
is not really bad.
Mother, I'm not uneducated and incompetent.
Think about it.
There are so many young women in the Xiang'an City.
Why is your third sister
chosen by the grand empress dowager?
It's because
her talents manners are so exceptional.
The First Madam has been educating her since she was young.
Music, chess, calligraphy, painting, poetry, and prose,
she excels in all of them.
But who would have thought that now
She's going to marry White Ghost
and enter his hell.
Mother.
Shen Du
is the of grand commander of the Imperial Security Bureau.
He's not as bad as you think.
Then do you think
the First Madam and your third sister
are just putting on an act with all their crying and fussing?
In short,
if your third sister marries him,
she will be
miserable,
painful,
anguished,
and tortured.